texashealth.org 2019-06-10

# Privacy Statement | Texas Health Resources

**Privacy and Confidentiality Policy**

TexasHealth.org is designed to comply with existing and proposed federal standards for the privacy and confidentiality of health care information. The database and software components are structured to provide that maintenance and routine troubleshooting occur with no access to your personal information. A security system helps protect against unauthorized access or misuse by authorized users.

All forms that request personal information (name, address, e-mail address, etc.) employ the https communications protocol to ensure secure and encrypted transmissions over the Internet.

Please read the Privacy Statements/Policies of our partners, linked below, which are external to the TexasHealth.org website. When selected, each will open in a new browser window. If you choose to conduct an online transaction with one of these companies, you may be required to submit personally identifiable information (PII). This PII is not kept or stored by Texas Health Resources. Texas Health has no control of how information is handled by these sites. Please read the privacy policy of the respective partner to understand how your PII may be disclosed, contained and maintained. Contact the partners directly with any questions.

  * [Flower and Gift Delivery](http://www.bestflowers.com/PU_Privacy.cfm) \- BestFlowers.com 
  * [Online Bill Pay](https://einvoice.ipayxepay.net/thr/ei_P11_F1_standard.jsp) \- Internet Payment Exchange 
  * [Web Nursery Baby Photos](http://www.our365.com/aboutus/privacy.aspx) \- Our365.com 

**Access and Disclosure**

TexasHealth.org does not disclose or provide access to any personal information to anyone without your permission, unless ordered to do so by a court of law or otherwise required by law. There may be isolated instances in which the staff must access the database to repair problems. Any access to individual files is carefully controlled. Staff members must document the need for access, log details of the access when complete, and confirm to management that they have accessed only task-critical areas and are in compliance with confidentiality policies.

**Links to Third Party Sites**

The TexasHealth.org Internet site may contain links to other Internet sites ("Linked Sites"). Links are strictly for informational purposes, and the appropriateness of such links is based on the judgment of the TexasHealth.org Internet Work Group. The Linked Sites are most likely not under the control of Texas Health Resources, and Texas Health Resources is not responsible for the content of any Linked Site that it does not control, including without limitation any link contained in a Linked Site, or any changes or updates to a Linked Site. Texas Health Resources is not responsible for webcasting or any other form of transmission received from any Linked Site. Texas Health Resources provides these links as a convenience, and the inclusion of any link does not imply endorsement of the site by Texas Health Resources or any association with its operators.

Linked sites will open in a new browser window, clearly indicating to users that they are leaving the TexasHealth.org Internet site. Texas Health Resources annually re-evaluates all external health related websites to which it links.

**Passive Tracking Mechanisms**

TexasHealth.org is firmly committed to protecting the privacy of website visitors. TexasHealth.org uses Web logs and temporary Internet cookies to gather aggregate, not individual data, about site visitors. We use remarketing tracking pixels and visitor browsing data to serve internet advertising to past site visitors and to reach similar audiences.

The following information is contained in these Web logs:

  * The date and time of the visit as well as length of stay 
  * The pages of TexasHealth.org viewed during the visit 
  * The IP address of the computer used to visit the site 
  * The type of Web browser and operating system used to view the site 
  * The Internet domain from which a visitor accessed the site 

TexasHealth.org uses Web logs as a way of conducting basic market research and to study how the site is being used. TexasHealth.org periodically analyzes the Web logs and may implement improvements or refinements based on information in the Web logs.

Cookies are packets of information that a website transfers to a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. They are a means of keeping track of a user's preferences during a visit to a Web site. Some services on our website use multi-session cookies, also known as “persistent cookies.” Persistent cookies are:

  * Small bits of text temporarily stored in your computer
  * Placed on your computer for more than a single session
  * Used to differentiate between new and returning site visitors, to customize our website for frequent visitors, and to assess site design and content 

Persistent cookies placed on your computer will expire two years after your last visit to our website. Texas Health uses cookies from third party vendors to serve ads based on past visits to TexasHealth.org

**Use and Sharing of Cookie Data**

We do not use session cookies or persistent cookies to collect PHI and we do not share any data collected from cookies.

If you do not want information to be collected via cookies, you can turn off cookies in your browser. To turn off cookies in Microsoft Internet Explorer, choose Tools from the top navigation, select Internet Options, choose Privacy and change the settings for TexasHealth.org. Information on TexasHealth.org may be read with cookies turned off.

We collect and store no other information about you when you visit our site unless you choose to provide it. For example:

  * If you send us an email or submit an online form, we will receive only the personal information you include in the form.

**Phone numbers**

Texas Health may collect information on calls to numbers listed on the Texas Health website and marketing materials. This information includes the caller’s phone number, the name displayed on the Caller ID and other caller information (such as call source, call duration, location, device).

Texas Health uses analytics tools developed by approved vendors to analyze the activity of interactions as consumers use our website and our products and services. Texas Health uses information collected to improve customer experience and website performance. Information is collected in a HIPAA-complaint platform and is not shared with third-parties for marketing purposes.

**Spyware  **

TexasHealth.org does not deploy spyware or any software that aids in gathering information about a person or organization without their knowledge and which may send such information to another entity without the consumer's consent.

**Site Sponsorship**

Texas Health Resources is the sole sponsor of all content on TexasHealth.org. No other company or organization contributes funding for the site.

**Texas Health Resources Corporate Office**   
612 E. Lamar Blvd., Suite 900    
Arlington, TX 76011   
682-236-7900
